{"Topic": "Metals and Alloys", "Subject": "General Knowledge", "Data": [{"Question": "Which one of the following metals is the best conductor of electricity?", "op1": "iron", "op2": "copper", "op3": "silver", "op4": "aluminium", "Answer": 4}, {"Question": "Which of the following is the lightest metal?", "op1": "mercury", "op2": "copper", "op3": "aluminium", "op4": "lithium", "Answer": 3}, {"Question": "Which two metals combine to form Bell metal?", "op1": "nickel and copper", "op2": "zinc and copper", "op3": "tin and copper", "op4": "brass and nickel", "Answer": 1}, {"Question": "Which of the following metals is known to pollute the air of big cities with a large number of vehicles?", "op1": "Lead", "op2": "Mercury", "op3": "Iron", "op4": "Copper", "Answer": 2}, {"Question": "Which of the following metals is used in making the filament of an electric bulb?", "op1": "platinum", "op2": "tungsten", "op3": "carbon", "op4": "chromium", "Answer": 4}, {"Question": "Which one among the following metals is used for making boats because it does not corrode by seawater?", "op1": "Tungsten", "op2": "Nickel", "op3": "Antimony", "op4": "Titanium", "Answer": 1}, {"Question": "Which one of the following metals/alloys is used in electric heating elements?", "op1": "Nichrome", "op2": "Chromium", "op3": "Steel", "op4": "Bronze", "Answer": 2}, {"Question": "Why are noble metals so named?", "op1": "Because they are expensive", "op2": "Because they are generally resistant to corrosion and oxidation", "op3": "Because they are rarely found in the earth", "op4": "Because they are more malleable and ductile than others", "Answer": 3}, {"Question": "Due to its reactivity, the alkali metal sodium is stored in -", "op1": "water", "op2": "alcohol", "op3": "kerosene", "op4": "ethanol", "Answer": 4}, {"Question": "Thin foils of which of the following metals are used in decorating sweets?", "op1": "steel", "op2": "aluminium", "op3": "chromium", "op4": "silver", "Answer": 4}, {"Question": "Which of the following metals has been used in making the Statue of Liberty?", "op1": "gold", "op2": "iron", "op3": "bronze", "op4": "copper", "Answer": 3}, {"Question": "Metals are good conductors of electricity because", "op1": "they are electrically unstable", "op2": "atoms in their molecules are loosely packed", "op3": "they have free electrons", "op4": "they are ductile", "Answer": 3}, {"Question": "Into which of the following metals does radioactive Uranium decay when it loses all its radioactivity?", "op1": "Radium", "op2": "Carbon", "op3": "Lead", "op4": "Hydrogen", "Answer": 3}, {"Question": "Galvanized iron has a thin coating of :", "op1": "copper", "op2": "tin", "op3": "zinc", "op4": "aluminium", "Answer": 2}, {"Question": "Plumbism is a condition due to the poisoning effect of -", "op1": "lead", "op2": "mercury", "op3": "copper", "op4": "uranium", "Answer": 4}, {"Question": "Duralumin is an alloy of copper and", "op1": "lead", "op2": "zinc", "op3": "tin", "op4": "aluminium", "Answer": 2}, {"Question": "In which of the following metals is the speed of sound the fastest?", "op1": "copper", "op2": "aluminium", "op3": "steel", "op4": "gold", "Answer": 2}, {"Question": "Which of the following is the heaviest metal?", "op1": "gold", "op2": "osmium", "op3": "mercury", "op4": "lead", "Answer": 4}, {"Question": "Which of the following gases is responsible for discolouration of brass in air?", "op1": "nitrogen oxide", "op2": "carbon dioxide", "op3": "water vapour", "op4": "hydrogen sulphide", "Answer": 2}, {"Question": "Which of the following metals forms an amalgam with other metals?", "op1": "magnesium", "op2": "mercury", "op3": "manganese", "op4": "molybdenum", "Answer": 1}, {"Question": "Which of the following metals is central to chlorophyll, the pigment which gives green colour to leaves of plants?", "op1": "magnesium", "op2": "manganese", "op3": "aluminium", "op4": "sodium", "Answer": 2}, {"Question": "Supplements containing which of the following metals are generally prescribed for persons suffering from anaemia?", "op1": "calcium", "op2": "iron", "op3": "gold", "op4": "magnesium", "Answer": 4}, {"Question": "Nichrome is used as heating element because of its -", "op1": "low resistivity and high melting point", "op2": "high resistivity and low melting point", "op3": "low resistivity and high melting ppoint", "op4": "high resistivity and high melting point", "Answer": 1}]}